Marty Ross

510-969-6066 — mdross510@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/mdross510/

Career Summary

Accomplished engineer with more than ten years of full-stack experience in API design, inter-process communication, subsystem and component architecture, implementation, maintenance and evolution. Dedicated to consistently establishing clear requirements, code readability, automated testing and strategic refactoring to counter software entropy across a variety of business domains. Reputation for mastery of subject material, providing excellent customer service, and mentoring other team members through a collaborative, always-learning, growth mindset.

Skills

- ❖ Golang (1.16, 1.20), Python (2.x, 3.x), Node.js with Typescript
- Java Application Development (J2ME, J2SE, J2EE)
- Java / Spring Boot / Spring Security & OAuth2
- ❖ Microservice Integration using REST, gRPC & Event Bus
- TDD using "Testing Pyramid" (Fowler; e.g. with golang tests, Junit, Jest)
- Persistence: DynamoDB, Cassandra, Kafka KTable, Redis, SQL, JPA/Hibernate
- Cloud Providers: AWS/CloudFormation, GCP/Terraform
- Message Busses: Kafka, RabbitMQ, Mulesoft, SQS/SNS/EventBridge
- Serverless: AWS Lambdas, Cloud Functions, Step Functions, Workflows

Professional Experience

Crunchyroll (San Francisco, CA) 04/2021 - 02/2023 Sr. Software Engineer

- Led enterprise initiatives by driving clarity in requirements, design and implementation within team and across departments
- Increased throughput and reduced complexity by eliminating constraining linkages between services through restructuring
- Increased code coverage by 20% across critical legacy service codebases, resulting in greater stability and confidence
- Optimized database access plans increasing service throughput by 20- 50%
- Hastened resolution of "sev 1" issues through enriched service instrumentation feeds to dashboards
- Maintained updated documentation (e.g., Runbooks, OpenAPI) and blogged on team-wide issues & initiatives
- Mentored junior developers through peering on solutions and giving thoughtful code reviews

Self Employed (Berkeley, CA) 05/2020 - 02/2021 Part Time Consultant

- Embraced several paid and unpaid opportunities in the first year of the COVID epidemic:
- Used the Java Play Framework to maintain a customer website
- Created a new data processing pipeline using Spring Batch toolset
- Maintained and enhanced a non-profit website using WordPress

Revinate (San Francisco, CA) 04/2018 - 04/2020 Staff Engineer

- As a key contributor of the Data Integrations team, responsible for ETL (extract, transform, load) of customer data
- Created extendable "script plug-in" service to retrieve customer data across sources, empowering Field Technicians
- Added "data replay" using Kafka offsets and KTables, empowering customers with iterative fixup re-ingestion
- Coordinated and supervised offshore development team, increasing business alignment
- Designed and led development of new functionality and supported legacy services
- Assisted on-boarding through mentoring new team members

Navis (Oakland, CA) 10/2011 - 12/2017 Staff Engineer

- Architected Equipment Control Interface (ECI) facade API to control Automated Guided Vehicles and Cranes
- Reduced MTTR by 15% through instrumentation providing visualized traces of protocol interactions with external equipment
- Educated others by providing mentoring, peer reviews, frequent blog posts and presentations at lunch and learn forums
- Wrote CI/CD tooling and test coverage reporting as an avid champion of test driven development (TDD)

Education / Training

Bachelor of Arts (BA)
University of California (Los Angeles, CA)
Economics, Psychology (with emphasis on econometrics and statistics)